- Did that kill it?
- No.
That's how we kill it.
The Book of Vishanti!
We can't let it take your power.
Get to the book.
- How do we get across?
- Jump.
Hold on!
No, no, no!
It's too strong.
I can't hold it.
I'm so sorry.
This is the only way.
What're you doing?
I can't let that thing take your power.
You can't control it.
But I can.
But we're friends.
You're killing me.
I know.
But in the grand calculus
of the Multiverse,
your sacrifice
is worth more than your...
Excuse me. May I?
Thanks.
Doctor Strange.
Doctor West.
Haven't seen you in a while.
Yeah, I was a little preoccupied
being dust there for five years, so...
So were a lot of us.
While I was gone,
thank you for asking,
I lost both my cats...
and my brother.
I'm very sorry.
Thank you.
I, uh...
I guess what keeps me up
at night is wondering,
did it have to happen that way?
Was there any other path?
No.
No, I made the only play we had.
Well, of course you did.
The best surgeon and the best superhero.
But you still didn't get the girl.
Glass of red, please.
- Oh, allow me, miss.
- Mm.
- Ah.
- Little too on the nose?
What? For you, at my wedding?
Nah. I think it was perfect.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Mm. There's Charlie.
I have to introduce you
because he's kind of...
It's embarrassing,
but he's a big fan, so...
Hey, uh, Christine. Um...
I should've...
I wish I'd have been different.
I never stopped caring about us.
But I had to make sacrifices
to protect you.
I'm sorry.
It was never gonna work out
between us.
Why not?
Because, Stephen,
you have to be the one
holding the knife.
And I always respected you for it,
but I couldn't love you for it.
How long you had that one
in the barrel?
Long time.
Yeah. I bet.
Look, um...
Truly, I'm just glad that you're happy.
Mm.
I am.
I really, really am.
Good.
Are you?
I'm happy.
Good.
You deserve it.
Oh, man.
Look out! What is that?
Dude!
Thank you.
Wow!
No, no.
Look out!
Do I know you?
Help!
You're welcome.
You know it's ancient custom
to bow in the presence
of the Sorcerer Supreme?
Yeah, I'm aware of the customs.
Hold it, hold it! Whoa!
Whoa.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
Oh, God!
Who's this?
Yeah, I was gonna ask the same question.
Hey, kid.
What did that creature want with you?
Where're your parents?
We'll take her back to the Sanc...
She took my Slingie.
She took your Slingie.
Yeah, it was crazy, man.
Oh, my God!
I'm not gonna kill you, kid.
I just bust my ass
trying to save your life, remember?
Giant monsters I can clearly handle,
but what bothers me is that last night,
you were in my dream.
That wasn't a dream.
It was another universe.
How much experience do you guys have
with the Multiverse?
We have experience of the Multiverse.
Most recently, there was
an incident with Spider-Man.
What man?
Spider-Man.
He has the powers of a spider.
- Hence the name.
- Gross.
- Does he look like a spider?
- No. No, more like a man.
Climbs walls, shoots webs.
- Yeah. Bingo.
- Out of his butt?
No.
Well, maybe, I don't know.
Honestly, I hope not.
Super weird.
You're gonna get a stomach ache.
I'm from another universe.
How do you know my stomach
works the same as yours?
I don't.
I don't even know
if you're from another universe,
which is why I'm still sitting here,
waiting for you
to enlighten us.
Gotta say,
of the two Doctor Stranges
I've met so far...
...you're not my favorite.
Which means?
Does he not know Spanish?
I'm not sure
he even enjoys speaking English.
Look,
I left a very nice wedding
to save a smart-ass kid
from getting eaten by an octopus.
- Whose wedding?
- Now tell me...
- Christine's.
- You went?
Holy shit, you married Christine?
- Do you mind?
- Yes, I do.
No, I didn't. Yes.
You need to explain to me
what's going on.
Why was that octopus trying to eat you?
That thing was trying to kidnap me.
It's like a henchman
who works for a demon.
All we knew is that they wanted
to take my power for themselves.
What power?
I can travel the Multiverse.
What?
You can physically move
from one universe to another?
- Mm-hmm.
- How?
That's the problem.
I don't know how.
Can't control it.
Only happens when
I'm really, really afraid.
Okay. And did Other Me know
how to defeat this demon?
Well, you guys knew
of this magical book of pure good
that gives a sorcerer whatever they need
to defeat their enemy.
The Book of Vishanti?
It's not real.
It's a fairy tale.
It doesn't exist.
Actually, it does.
I found out in the secret book you get
when you become Sorcerer Supreme.
Unbelievable.
You're not the Sorcerer Supreme?
No, I'm not the Sorcerer Supreme.
Other You was Sorcerer Supreme
of his universe.
Right. Yeah.
Although it does exist,
the Book of Vishanti
is said to be unreachable.
It is. Except...
we reached it.
Then the demon caught up with us.
I thought you'd protect me...
but you didn't.
That was the fight in my dream.
That wasn't a dream.
Prove it.
It wasn't a dream.
That means...
dreams are windows into the lives
of our Multiversal selves.
That was his theory.
So, that recurring nightmare
where I'm running naked from a clown...
Somewhere out there, it's real.
Somewhere out there I had a ponytail.
There could be
more creatures coming for her.
The power is dangerous enough
in the hands of a kid.
Imagine if a real threat acquired it?
It occurs to me, young one,
we don't know your name.
America Chavez.
Miss Chavez, will you come
with us to Kamar-Taj?
You'll be safe there.
How do I know you won't
betray me like he did?
I guess you're just
gonna have to trust me.
What do we do with him?
That's gotta violate an ordinance.
Ah, I've buried worse.
The creature that killed him, did...
did it have the same markings
as the octopus?
Runes.
This isn't sorcery.
It's witchcraft.
Do we know anyone
who's faced such a thing?
I think I might.
- Chocolate!
- Hey! What did I say?
But we couldn't wait.
But what did I say?
Oh!
Go wash your hands.
Mom, come on.
We're too old for that.
Oh, okay.
You can tuck me in, Mom.
I will.
You know, a family is forever.
We could never truly leave each other,
even if we tried.
Mom, I changed my mind.
You can come tuck me in if you want.
Okay.
Love you.
Apples, right?
- Eventually.
- Hmm.
- Smells...
- Sweet.
I was gonna say real.
Oh, it's all very real, thanks.
I've put the magic behind me.
So I can see.
Well, I knew sooner or later
you'd show up,
wanting to discuss
what happened at Westview.
I made mistakes,
and people were hurt...
But you put things right in the end,
and that was never in doubt.
I'm not here to talk about Westview.
Then what are you here for?
We need your help.
With what?
What do you know about the Multiverse?
The Multiverse.
Vis had his theories.
He believed it was real,
and dangerous.
Well, he was right about both.
We found a girl
who can somehow travel across it,
but she's being pursued.
- Pursued by who?
- Some kind of demon.
- One that covets her power for itself.
- Ah.
We've taken her to Kamar-Taj,
and we've got our defenses,
but we could use an Avenger.
There are other Avengers.
Yeah, but given the choice
between the archer with the mohawk
and several bug-themed crime fighters,
or one of the most powerful
magic-wielders on the planet...
...it's an easy call.
Come to Kamar-Taj.
It'll get you back on the lunch box.
What if you brought America here?
Here?
Yeah. I know what it's like
to be on your own,
hunted for abilities you never wanted,
and I can protect her.
You never told me her name, did you?
No.
- Mm.
- No, I didn't.
You know, the Hex was the easy part.
The lying, not so much.
The Darkhold.
You're familiar with the Darkhold?
I know it's the Book of the Damned,
and that it corrupts everything
and everyone that it touches.
I wonder what it's done to you.
The Darkhold only showed me the truth.
Everything I lost can be mine again.
What do you want with America?
What do you want with the Multiverse?
I'm going to leave this reality
and go to one where I can be
with my children.
Wanda, your children aren't real.
You created them using magic.
That's what every mother does.
If you knew
there was a universe
where you were happy,
wouldn't you want to go there?
I am happy.
I know better than most
what self-deception looks like.
What you're doing is a flagrant violation
of every natural law,
and if you take that child's power,
she won't survive.
I don't relish hurting anyone, Stephen.
But she's not a child.
She's a supernatural being.
Such raw power could wreak havoc on this
and other worlds.
Her sacrifice
would be for the greater good.
Well, you can kiss the lunch box goodbye,
'cause that's the kind of justification
our enemies use.
Is it the one you used
when you gave Thanos the Time Stone?
That was a war,
and I did what I had to do.
You break the rules and become a hero.
I do it, and I become the enemy.
That doesn't seem fair.
What happens now?
Return to Kamar-Taj
and prepare to hand over
America Chavez by sundown.
Peacefully.
After that...
You'll never see me again.
And if we don't?
Then it won't be Wanda
who comes for her.
It will be the Scarlet Witch.
The Scarlet Witch.
Wanda's gone.
She's got the Darkhold,
and the Darkhold has her.
The Scarlet Witch is
a being of unfathomable magic.
She can rewrite reality as she chooses,
and is prophesized to either rule
or annihilate the cosmos.
She took over a whole town using her mind.
If she gets America's power,
she could enslave the entire Multiverse.
So, the person you went to ask for help,
and told exactly where I am,
is the person that's trying to kill me?
Yeah.
Suspend teaching at once
and arm the students.
Kamar-Taj must now become a fortress.
Wow.
It's the masters of the Hong Kong
and London Sanctums.
It's an honor to court death
alongside you once again.
The honor is ours.
Whatever the
Sorcerer Supreme asks of us,
it shall be done.
Extra duty men,
follow me.
It's ancient custom.
Choose your words wisely.
The fate of the Multiverse
may depend on it.
Got it.
No pressure, then.
All this for a child you met yesterday.
Wanda, you are justifiably angry.
You had to make terrible sacrifices.
I blew a hole through the head
of the man I loved,
and it meant nothing.
Do not speak to me of sacrifice,
Stephen Strange.
If you give me what I want,
I'll send you to a world where
you can be with Christine.
The full might of Kamar-Taj
stands against you.
Defensive positions, now!
Do not dare to enter these sacred grounds.
You have no idea
just how reasonable I have been.
Yeah.
Book of the Damned,
calling yourself a witch,
conjuring creatures to abduct a kid,
I don't exactly call that
being reasonable.
Sending those creatures
after her instead of myself
was mercy.
And in spite of your hypocrisies,
and insults,
I have begged you
to safely get out of my way.
You have exhausted my patience,
but I do hope you understand
that even now,
what's about to happen,
this is me
being reasonable.
Hold!
Nailed it.
Reinforce the shield.
Reinforce the shield!
She's trying to get in their heads.
Sorcerers, fortify your mind!
Run.
The shield is down!
Fire!
Yes!
Take cover!
Fire at will!
Fall back.
Wong!
Get out of here!
Go, go.
Go!
America...
You want the girl,
you'll have to go through me.
Fine.
We gotta get you out of here. Now.
Wong, what happened?
Kamar-Taj has fallen.
Reflections.
She's using the reflections.
Cover them.
You gave all those lives
just to keep me from my children.
You took those lives.
You cannot be allowed
to cross into the Multiverse.
I'm not a monster, Stephen.
I'm a mother.
Wanda, you have no children.
They don't exist.
Oh, but they do.
In every other universe.
I know they do.
Because I dream of them
every night.
We're gonna show it.
Mom, watch us. Mom!
Go long. Got it!
All right, go on back, go on back.
All right, yeah. Don't...
Of my boys.
Billy, don't you dare! No!
Of our life together.
- Here.
- Yes!
And then back to front.
Back to front.
Can I have some?
Please?
- Are you guys ready?
- It's okay.
I love you, Mom.
Every night...
the same dream.
And every morning...
the same nightmare.
What if you reach them?
What happens to the other you?
What happens to their mother?
You okay?
You saved me.
I hope so.
Surprised you didn't puke.
It's not my first weird trip, kid.
So, this is New York
in the Multi...
Yep.
There it is.
Crap.
Cut it out.
Yeah, you got pretty dinged up.
We'll get you fixed.
All right, America.
You gotta open a portal
and get us back there right now.
I don't know how.
You just did it.
Not on purpose.
Wong is back there alone with Wanda,
and I'm the only hope he has.
I can't control my powers...
You must be able to control it somehow.
Even I could...
Sorry.
Well, what about this
universe's version of you?
Maybe she could
control her powers.
This universe doesn't have a me.
- What?
- None of them do.
But how do you know that?
'Cause I've looked.
And 'cause I never dream.
That's okay, kid.
And even if you could get me back there,
I have no way of fighting Wanda.
What about The Book of Vishanti?
What about it?
Other You thought it could stop
whoever was after me.
Yeah, well, good for Other Me.
He's not here, is he?
I don't know where it is,
so unless there's another Other Me...
We need to go find...
Other Other Me.
We go on red?
Rule number one of Multiversal travel,
you don't know anything.
Right.
It's red.
So, what's rule number 2?
America?
America!
Rule number 2,
find food.
Preferably pizza. Pizza balls.
How'd you pay for that?
It was free.
Food's free
in most universes, actually.
It's weird you guys have to pay for it.
- Hey! You didn't pay for that.
- Right.
Crap.
Maybe it's not free here.
Pizza Poppa always gets paid.
All right, Pizza Poppa, relax.
She's just a kid...
- She was hungry.
- Relax yourself, there,
Doctor Strange.
Where'd you get
this cape from, anyway?
Oh, that feels authentic.
It's not a cape, it's a cloak,
and I suggest you let go.
You took this whole suit
from the Strange Museum, didn't you?
- Strange Museum?
- You're a taker.
Why don't you take some mustard, huh?
Come on. It's not permanent.
Like he'll stop in a few minutes?
About 3 weeks.
Those universes we went through,
were we paint in one of them?
Yeah, you don't wanna get stuck in there.
It's really hard to eat.
How many universes have you been to?
Uh...
72.
73, counting this one.
That's...
That's a lot.
Memory Lane.
Replay your significant memories,
now at a discounted price.
We remember so you don't forget.
This is pretty fancy.
Did you have to take out
another student loan?
Nah. I just sold one of those kidneys
that we operated on last week.
So, um, got you a little something.
Congratulations.
What is it?
Open it and see.
Christine, this is...
This is amazing. Thank you.
We don't have time for this.
Memory Lane.
Replay your significant memories,
now at a discounted price.
We remember so you don't forget.
Where's this?
Home.
My moms.
Son mis madres.
¿Para mí? Ay, qué linda.
Gracias.
A ver, te la pongo.
Mm. Tan hermosa.
Te ves bella.
Ándale, nos van a dar otra flor.
America!
You know, you were right.
This is just a waste of time.
Hey, kid.
That was the first time
that you opened a portal, right?
Doesn't matter.
It does matter.
You lost your parents.
I didn't lose them.
I killed them.
No. No, you did not.
Don't even think that.
Okay, I opened a portal
with the powers I can't control
and sent them to a random,
probably deadly universe,
- with no way to escape.
- Listen,
if your moms are
anything like their daughter,
they survived.
I'm sure you'll meet them again someday.
Not bad.
Thanks.
That woman in your memory bank thing,
that was Christine, right?
Yes, that was Christine.
- How do you know her?
- From Other You.
Were they together?
No, they didn't talk anymore.
He blew it.
Of course.
Did you blow it with your Christine?
Yes, I guess I did.
Why?
Complicated.
More complicated
than being chased by a witch
through the Multiverse?
Yes, actually, it is.
"Gave his life defeating Thanos"?
Yeah. See? We're not all bad.
If Other You's dead,
who's Master of the Sanctum?
Oh, shit.
- You know him?
- Yeah. Mordo.
He was actually the first guy
who let me into Kamar-Taj.
Oh, great.
And then he snapped
and dedicated his life
to trying to kill me.
Oh.
Great.
I always suspected
this day would come.
You did?
Yes.
Because you always suspected
this day would come.
My brother.
All right.
Come in,
and tell me everything
about your universe.
You go on red.
And you're quite
formidable too, it seems.
A Multiversal traveler.
Well, thank the stars
you brought Doctor Strange to safety.
Well, just 'cause we jumped ship
doesn't mean we're safe.
Our Wanda has the ability
to conjure demons and monsters
to attack America in other universes.
So she has the Darkhold?
Oh, you know of the Darkhold?
Oh, yes. We have a Darkhold
in this universe, too.
I guard it here in this Sanctum.
We would never
risk a weapon that dangerous
falling into the wrong hands.
Damn right.
But if your Darkhold
is anything like ours,
I'm afraid she can do far worse
than just summon monsters
to come after you here.
What do you mean?
There is a spell contained
within those pages...
...corrosive to the soul,
a desecration of reality itself.
Dreamwalking.
A Dreamwalking sorcerer
projects their own consciousness
from their universe into another,
possessing the body of an alternate self.
They may puppeteer
this unholy doppelganger
and pursue their enemies from afar.
The possession is not a permanent link
between realities.
But in the fleeting time they Dreamwalk,
they can do irreparable damage
to the universe they invade.
So it may not be a demon that you face.
It may be the Scarlet Witch.
Why didn't she do that to begin with?
Because that
was her being reasonable.
What do you know of The Book of Vishanti?
The Darkhold's antithesis?
It can give a sorcerer
whatever power they need
to vanquish their enemy.
I need your help
to get me to it.
I'm sorry, Stephen.
But I hope you,
of all people, understand
that it is not Wanda Maximoff
who threatens our reality,
it's the two of you.
- Oh, God.
- What was in that tea?
You son of a bitch.
The Sands of Nisanti.
I'm only acting as you would.
She's coming.
Boys, it's time for bed.
Can we have
a little more ice cream?
- Please.
- Please, please, please!
A little more, please!
Hey, don't make Mom
out to be the bad guy.
You know who's the best?
- Who?
- 2003 Tigers.
They suck.
They're so bad they suck egg.
No, they don't.
They're the best.
- Doofus.
- Doofus 2.
Triple infinity doofus.
Infinity infinity
googolplex quadruple doofus.
Quintuple infinity...
Crazy doofus.
Googolplex doofus.
Mom?
Yes, sweetheart?
Where are you going?
Just to take out the trash.
Can we show you something?
Mom, hurry, come on!
Come on, it's important.
Mom.
You'll like it.
Come on. Hurry up.
It's important.
Okay, so, Mom, listen to this...
I'm gonna start it.
- No, I wanna start it.
- I wanna start it.
- I want to start!
- No, I want to start!
- No! I want to start.
- I want to start.
Why don't you both start it,
whatever it is, together?
Okay.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
3, 2, 1, go.
We like ice cream
Like every child should
And if we get some ice cream
We promise to be good
You're alive.
Yes.
But so many others were lost.
Set me free.
I need to destroy the book.
No. It cannot be you.
Sara. No, no!
Mom!
What happened?
- What?
- Are you okay?
Okay. Billy, Tommy.
What?
No, no, no.
I need the Darkhold's spells.
You are the Sorcerer Supreme.
Tell me what you know.
You're gonna have to kill me, witch.
Not you.
Them.
Wanda, stop.
Wanda, please!
The Darkhold was a copy!
A copy?
Legend speaks of a mountain
with the wretched spells you seek
carved into its walls.
It's there the Darkhold was transcribed.
Mount Wundagore.
Wundagore?
No one has survived the journey.
Perhaps we will be the exception.
Hey!
This universe sucks.
Cloak?
Hey.
Hey, lab coat.
Where the hell are we?
Look, I don't know who you are,
or what you think
you're trying to do here,
but these situations don't usually...
- Thank you.
- ...work out well
for the nameless scientists, so just...
Christine?
Hello, Stephen.
Ay Dios.
Miss Chavez.
Uh, to answer your question,
you are in a highly secure
research facility.
The two of you,
along with your sentient cloak,
are here for surveillance and testing.
Uh... Uh, testing?
Well, yes.
You're visitors from another universe.
Your magnetic signatures
could be radioactive,
you may be carrying diseases
we just don't have treatments for.
Hence, these amazing
polycarbonate fish bowls.
I assume I have you
to thank for these then?
Yes. I developed those
using the Sands of Nisanti.
One of 838 Stephen's magical relics.
838 Stephen?
Is that some kind of cyborg me, or...
Our universe is 838,
and we've designated yours 616.
Oh. You guys sure must know
a lot about the Multiverse
if you got someone
going around naming realities.
Yes.
Me.
I'm a senior fellow
with the Baxter Foundation,
and I specialize in Multiversal research.
So,
how'd you end up working here?
Wherever here is.
Well, I volunteered.
At your funeral.
Thank you for going.
Your injuries, they're similar,
but they're not identical.
It's fascinating.
What were we to each other
in this universe?
We never quite figured that out.
Yeah?
Well, that's something we got in common.
Christine, you gotta let us out of here.
Everyone's in real danger.
Look, I know you don't know me...
And I don't want to.
Whatever I was to you in your universe
does not matter.
Why not?
Because you're dangerous, Stephen.
Someone from my universe
wants that girl,
and she's gonna rip this place
apart atom-by-atom
until she gets what she wants.
So I don't care
if you're from the Avengers
or S.H.I.E.L.D...
We're neither.
Well, what then?
HYDRA?
The Illuminati will see you now.
The Illumi-what-y?
Don't let anyone hurt that kid.
It's gonna be okay.
You couldn't portal us up there?
My magic can only take us so far.
Masters of the Mystic Arts
weren't meant to tread
upon the forbidden grounds of Wundagore.
Eons ago, the first demon, Chthon,
carved his dark magic into this tomb.
These same spells were later transcribed
into the Darkhold.
There's no telling
what soulless monstrosities lie within.
They've been waiting for me.
This isn't a tomb.
It's a throne.
Stephen Strange,
you are now called before the Illuminati.
I, Baron Karl Mordo,
the Sorcerer Supreme, do hereby...
"Karl"?
Captain Carter.
The first Avenger.
Blackagar Boltagon.
Keeper of the Terrigen Mists,
the Inhuman king.
Blackagar Boltagard? Huh.
Hidigy hidithere.
Captain Marvel.
Defender of the cosmos.
And the smartest man alive,
Reed Richards of the Fantastic Four.
Hello, Stephen.
"Fantastic Four."
Didn't you guys chart in the '60s?
I'm sorry, is this a joke to you?
Well, there's a guy over there
with a fork on his head,
so, yeah, a little bit.
Be grateful Black Bolt doesn't
engage you in conversation.
Why? Does he have bad breath?
This Strange is even
more arrogant than ours.
- Hmm.
- No, just more alive.
For now.
Stephen, your arrival here
confuses and destabilizes reality.
The larger the footprint you leave behind,
the greater the risk of an Incursion.
Incursion?
An Incursion occurs
when the boundary
between two universes erodes
and they collide,
destroying one or both entirely.
Your alternate self created the Illuminati
to make difficult decisions
that no one else could.
Today, we're here to determine
what to do with you and the child.
So, before we vote,
if you got anything serious to say,
now's the time.
Yeah, I do.
If it's Incursions you're worried about,
do you seriously think I'm a bigger threat
than the Scarlet Witch?
Oh, we can handle your little witch
if she decides to Dreamwalk.
No. No, you cannot.
Not unless you give me
The Book of Vishanti.
We appreciate your concern, Stephen,
but it's not the Scarlet Witch
that we fear.
From our experience, the greatest danger
to the Multiverse, it turns out,
is Doctor Strange.
Wait. Your Doctor Strange?
Earth's mightiest hero
who died defeating Thanos?
We should tell him the truth.
Our final member,
Professor Charles Xavier.
What truth?
That's not how our Strange died.
You're wondering what happens now.
No.
That I've already accepted.
But I do wonder
when you could force America
to send you to any universe you want,
why take her power for your own?
You know it would kill her.
For Billy and Tommy, to protect them.
What if they get sick?
In the infinite Multiverse,
there's a cure for every illness.
A solution to every problem.
I won't lose them again.
Try as you might, Wanda,
you cannot control everything.
But I can.
Look around you.
It's carved in stone.
I was meant to rule everything.
But that's not what I want.
I just want my boys.
At the cost of a child's life?
Is there no peace in knowing
that even though you can't be
with the ones you love,
there are worlds
where you are together?
Is that not enough?
No.
Our Strange did not die defeating Thanos.
We were at war.
While the rest of us banded together
to try to stop Thanos,
Stephen, as always, chose to go it alone.
He turned to the Darkhold,
began Dreamwalking,
in hopes that our salvation
might lie in the Multiverse.
And guess what?
It didn't.
But he kept doing it anyway.
One night,
you called us all together,
confessed that
you had been Dreamwalking,
and in your words,
"Things had gotten out of hand."
You never told us the details
of what had happened,
only that you had
inadvertently triggered
an Incursion.
You, our friend,
had caused the annihilation
of another universe.
Everyone in that reality died.
Everyone.
Stephen renounced the Darkhold's evil
and helped us find
The Book of Vishanti,
a weapon we did use together
to defeat Thanos.
But one final threat remained.
I shall miss you, my friend.
I'm ready.
I'm sorry.
Did you tell Christine?
Yes.
The statue...
What about the statue?
You built a statue.
The world needs heroes.
We made the difficult choice
because we knew what
our Strange was capable of.
What, perhaps,
every Doctor Strange is capable of.
The building's been breached.
No shit, genius.
Status report on sentries.
Stop where you...
Get back!
Stop where you are...
She's heading for the child.
Watch him.
We'll vote on our return.
Stephen, should you manage
to escape this chamber,
you must guide America Chavez.
What the hell are you saying?
Save the girl
and get to The Book of Vishanti.
What? You have the book here?
Yes. You built a waypoint.
Charles, we cannot trust him.
I believe we can.
Just because someone stumbles
and loses their way
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
We will see what kind
of Doctor Strange you are.
Thank you.
Perimeter breakdown.
All sentries engage.
Everybody out.
- Intruder approaching.
- Now!
It's Wanda.
Ultron commands you to halt.
Ultron commands...
Hurry, hurry! She's coming!
Oh, no.
Wanda, stop.
You've possessed an innocent woman,
but you can still do the right thing.
Let her go.
Please.
I have children of my own.
I understand your pain.
Is their mother still alive?
Yes.
Good. There will be
someone left to raise them.
Wanda, Black Bolt could destroy you
with one whisper from his mouth.
What mouth?
Take me to The Book of Vishanti,
so that we can fight her together.
You are in no position to give orders.
My vote will conclude these proceedings
when they return.
Haven't you had enough?
Oh, I could do this all day.
Get the hell out of my universe!
They're not coming back.
And you just cast your vote now
to kill your friends.
Not that that ever bothered you before.
You know, you hated me
where I came from.
And I bet secretly, my brother,
you hated me here.
You must've been so jealous.
Do you know what?
I bet you were thrilled
when you heard I'd been corrupted.
Hell, you probably gave me
the Darkhold to begin with...
You know nothing of this universe!
I know that killing Stephen Strange
was your ticket to getting the Sanctum,
to becoming Sorcerer Supreme,
and to joining
your little circus of clowns,
the Illuminati.
I'm ready...
to cast my vote now.
I think I'm beginning to understand
why your Mordo
didn't like you very much!
You're sealed shut!
Okay. Get back.
Whoa.
Enough!
Help me. Please.
Wanda Maximoff,
your mind is being held hostage
by your alternate self.
Grab my hand.
Perhaps, if I can pull you
from under the rubble,
the spell will break.
Hey! You all right?
You okay?
Hey.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Hey.
She fixed him.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Xavier said I built a waypoint
to The Book of Vishanti.
Can you take us there?
How am I supposed to trust you?
I know what happened,
and I'm sorry for what he did,
but believe me,
The Book of Vishanti is the only way.
Yeah. Your way.
You sound a lot
like my Stephen right now.
He had to be the one holding the knife,
and then that knife
killed a trillion people.
This Stephen is different.
He is.
It doesn't matter
about all the other Stephens.
You're not like them.
Smart kid.
Give me your hand.
Do not make me regret this.
I won't.
- Okay, can we go now?
- Yeah, follow me.
Where's that tunnel go?
Under the river.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Where did she go?
I warned you.
Other Wanda, if you're in there,
hold your breath.
- Did you kill her?
- No, just bought us some time.
The Book's through here.
But only Stephen's ever opened it.
Shit.
An enchantment
that's specific to me,
something only I would know.
- Wait. Stephen.
- Come on.
Come on.
Stephen.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Sure.
Open sesame.
Come on, kid.
You got this.
We got this.
Yeah.
You all right?
This is the Gap Junction,
the space between universes.
All right, Book.
Give me what I need.
No!
My boys.
This isn't what your children would want.
They'll never know.
Maybe not.
But you will.
Oh, no.
Oh, crap.
It's like this reality
collapsed in on itself.
Yeah.
Or two realities collided.
Come on.
America doesn't have long.
So where are we going?
Well,
if there's still a sanctum
in this universe,
then there might be
another Other Other Me,
and that's our best shot
of getting back to her.
Well, I can see why you guys
were so worried about Incursions.
Whatever happened,
this universe's you
didn't do a very good job
of stopping it.
I'll tell him you said that.
Hello?
Stop where you are.
How did you get here?
By accident.
Who are you?
What are you?
I'm just one of us.
From the Multiverse?
That's right.
Prove it.
We had a sister.
Donna.
But she, um...
She died when we were kids.
How?
We were playing
on a frozen lake and, uh...
she fell through the ice.
I couldn't save her.
Sounds about right.
But we don't talk about that, do we?
No, we don't.
Suppose your reality
wasn't always like this.
I suspect it was
somewhat like yours until...
Until?
Until I lost.
To whom?
What do you want?
I just want to get home.
Yeah? Believe me,
I've been trying to leave
this place for a long time.
Darkhold.
You guard the Darkhold in this universe?
Yeah.
For good reason.
That's a start.
I could use it.
It could help me to communicate
with my universe.
Careful.
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
I don't mean to be callous,
but how much of a heavier toll
is there left to exact?
Not just on its reality.
On its reader.
Look, I'm sorry you couldn't
save your universe,
but maybe you could help
to save mine.
Are you happy, Stephen?
What?
It's the question that...
Christine Palmer
asked me at her wedding.
I said, "Yes, of course I'm happy.
"I'm a sorcerer with the power of gods.
"What man wouldn't be happy?"
And then I came back
to this goddamn haunted house,
sat down,
and wondered why I'd lied.
I never meant for any of this to happen.
I was looking for a world
where things were different.
Where I had Christine,
where I was happy.
But I didn't find it.
All I found were more of us.
So I did those Stephens a favor.
You ever had that dream
where you're falling
as if you've been pushed off
a tall building?
That was probably me.
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
Okay.
All the more reason to give it a rest
and let me have it.
Here's the deal.
I'll let you use the Darkhold
if you give me your Christine.
Yeah.
I don't think she's gonna go for that.
No?
Didn't think so.
Hang on, we're coming.
What are you doing with the Darkhold?
Are you going to Dreamwalk?
It's a little bit more
than just Dreamwalking.
All you Stranges, you're the same.
I know.
You're right.
We are all the same.
But right now, that kid needs me.
And I can't do any of this
without your help.
While I'm under,
I need you to protect my body
in case they attack me for trespassing.
Who's "they"?
The souls of the damned.
Okay.
But doesn't a version of you
need to live in that universe,
so that you can Dreamwalk into them?
Who said they had to be living?
Stephen Strange,
possessing a dead body is forbidden.
Forbidden.
Trespasser!
Cease your Dreamwalk,
or face the eternal consequences.
Stephen!
They're pulling me down.
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
Where are you?
The Brazier of Bom'Galiath.
Go back to hell.
Stephen.
I've got you.
You're a Master of the Mystic Arts.
They're spirits.
Use them.
No!
Come on!
Uh-oh.
Strange!
Dreamwalking. You hypocrite!
This time, it's gonna take
more than killing me
to kill me.
Murderer! Murderer!
I don't even wanna know.
No!
- No!
She's breaking free!
Hold her!
Strange, take America's power!
There's no other way.
Yeah.
This is the only way.
It's me in Other Me's body.
You're here to take my power,
aren't you?
Before Wanda can.
It's okay.
I understand now.
No, America.
I've come here to tell you
to trust yourself.
Trust your power.
That's how we stop her.
I can't control it. I...
Yes, you can.
You have been all along.
Every time you opened a portal,
you sent us
exactly where we needed to go.
What about the first time?
Even that led you to this moment...
when you're gonna kick that witch's ass.
I've got you.
Uh-huh.
Mm-mm-mm.
I can't beat you.
So I'll give you what you want.
Billy. Tommy.
Mommy!
It's the witch!
What have you done?
- Mom!
- Mommy!
Wait! Boys!
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay.
I'm your mother!
Get away from them.
Mom!
No.
Not yet.
Mommy!
- Get away from our mom!
- You're not our real mom!
Hey, boys. Stop. Please.
- Please. Boys, stop it.
- Get out of our house!
- You're not our mom!
- Get out!
- Go away!
- Go!
Stop it!
Please don't hurt us.
Please.
I would never hurt you.
Never.
I would never hurt anyone.
I'm not a monster.
I'm a...
I'm...
I'm sorry.
Mom!
- Are you okay?
- Hi.
Hi. Okay.
I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Mom, don't go. Don't go.
- No, Mom. Don't.
- It's okay.
- Mom.
It's okay. It's okay.
Know that they'll be loved.
What now?
Get out of here.
I'll find you.
We have to go. Now!
I opened the Darkhold.
I have to close it.
No one will ever be tempted
by the Darkhold again.
You all right?
- Is it over?
- Yeah.
Is America okay?
She's on her way here to get us.
Wanda?
No.
So she destroyed the Darkhold
in every universe.
She did the right thing.
Yeah, she did.
What's your universe like?
- It's very beautiful.
- Hmm.
I wish I could show you.
I'd really like that.
- But I have to go.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
It's too bad, though.
Could've been one hell of an Incursion.
I love you.
I love you in every universe.
It's not that
I don't wanna care for someone
or have someone care for me.
It's just...
I get scared.
Yeah.
Face your fears...
Doctor Strange.
Ay! How is this so much harder
than a Multiversal portal?
She needs to slow down
and be more patient.
Reminds me of another student I knew.
How you feeling?
Why do you ask?
You used the Darkhold
to Dreamwalk into your own corpse.
Oh.
Yeah, right, that.
Fine.
But I do wanna ask you something.
Are you happy?
That's a, um,
interesting question.
You'd think that saving the world
would get you there,
but it doesn't.
Sometimes, I do wonder
about my other lives.
Yet I remain grateful in this one.
Even with its tribulations.
At least we don't have to
go through it alone, huh?
No, we don't.
Hmm.
Wait.
'Sup?
'Sup.
Made some sparks.
Great.
Your parents would be proud.
I hope you'll get to show 'em one day.
Stephen.
I'm glad I fell into your universe.
So am I, kid.
So am I.
Hmm.
Doctor Strange?
Can I help you?
You caused an Incursion,
and we're gonna fix it.
Unless you're afraid.
Not in the least.
It's over!